# YANWEI LI

• ywli@cse.cuhk.edu.hk • yanwei-li.com • (+852) 6939-6373 Ho Sin-Hang Engineering Building, The Chinese University of Hong Kong.

### ABOUT ME

I'm Yanwei Li, a Ph.D student in Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), supervised by Prof. Jiaya Jia. My research interest mainly focuses on instance-level and semantic segmentation.

### **EDUCATION**

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Ph.D, Computer Science, 2024 (expected)

Fields: Computer Vision

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences

M.Phil, Pattern Recognition, 2020

Fields: Computer Vision

Central South University

B.E., Automation & Mechanical Engineering

Overall GPA: 89.52/100, Rank: Top 5%

Hong Kong, China

Sep. 2020 - Present

Beijing, China Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2020

Changsha, China Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

### EXPERIENCE

Megvii Research

Fields: Network design for segmentation

Research Intern

**Horizon Robotics** 

Fields: Panoptic segmentation

Research Intern

**IBM Research** 

Fields: Fine-grained recognition

Research Intern

Beijing, China

Jan. 2019 - Nov. 2020

Beijing, China Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Beijing, China

Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Fully Convolutional Networks for Panoptic Segmentation

Yanwei Li, Hengshuang Zhao, Xiaojuan Qi, Liwei Wang, Zeming Li, Jian Sun, Jiaya Jia

CVPR 2021 (Oral) [Paper] [Code]

Scale-aware Automatic Augmentation for Object Detection

Yukang Chen\*, Yanwei Li\*, Tao Kong, Lu Qi, Ruihang Chu, Lei Li, Jiaya Jia

**CVPR** 2021

Fine-Grained Dynamic Head for Object Detection

Lin Song, Yanwei Li, Zhengkai Jiang, Zhengkai Jiang, Zeming Li, Hongbin Sun, Jian Sun, Nanning Zheng

NeurIPS 2020 [Paper] [Code]

Rethinking Learnable Tree Filter for Generic Feature Transform

Lin Song, Yanwei Li, Zhengkai Jiang, Zeming Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Hongbin Sun, Jian Sun, Nanning Zheng

NeurIPS 2020 [Paper] [Code]

Learning Dynamic Routing for Semantic Segmentation

Yanwei Li, Lin Song, Yukang Chen, Zeming Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Xingang Wang, Jian Sun

CVPR 2020 (Oral) [Paper] [Code] [Slides]

Nov. 2020

Nov. 2020

Dec. 2020

Dec. 2020

Feb. 2020

<sup>\*</sup> denotes equal contribution

## Learnable Tree Filter for Structure-preserving Feature Transform Sep. 2019

Lin Song\*, Yanwei Li\*, Zeming Li, Gang Yu, Hongbin Sun, Jian Sun, Nanning Zheng

NeurIPS 2019 [Paper] [Code]

### Attention-guided Unified Network for Panoptic Segmentation

Feb. 2019

Yanwei Li, Xinze Chen, Zheng Zhu, Lingxi Xie, Guan Huang, Dalong Du, Xingang Wang

CVPR 2019 [Paper]

### Identity-Enhanced Network for Facial Expression Recognition

Oct. 2018

Yanwei Li, Xingang Wang, Shilei Zhang, Lingxi Xie, Wenqi Wu, Hongyuan Yu, Zheng Zhu

ACCV 2018 [Paper]

### **WORKSHOP & COMPETITION**



MicroSoft COCO 2018 Panoptic Challenge Yanwei Li\*, Naiyu Gao\*, Chaoxu Guo, et.al.

Munich, Germany

(\* denotes equal contribution)

- Achieve 2nd place
- Propose an end-to-end framework for panoptic segmentation with high performance.
- Oral in ECCV 2018 Workshop [Presentation]

### AWARDS AND HONORS

Post-Graduate Scholarship	2020-2024
National Scholarship (Top 0.2% students in China)	Nov, 2019
National Scholarship (Top 0.2% students in China)	Nov, 2016
National Encouragement Scholarship	Nov, 2015